### MATT BENSON

North Bend, WA 98045

Phone: 425-614-9155 | Email: rabenson6@msn.com

LinkedIn: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/matt-benson-b7a24a91/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/matt-benson-b7a24a91/</a> | Github: <a href="https://github.com/Bensonm3">https://github.com/Bensonm3</a> |

Portfolio: <a href="https://dry-temple-73836.herokuapp.com/">https://dry-temple-73836.herokuapp.com/</a>

#### SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with a background in Political Science, International Business, and a passion for learning. Seasoned project manager with over 5 years of experience, capable of working independently and collaborating with teams across multiple functions. Hands on experience coding in Javascript, HTML, and CSS as well as working with React, jQuery, SQL databases, and Python scripting.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Javascript, HTML, CSS, Python

Applications: React, Typescript, Node.js, Express.js, Bootstrap, jQuery, Git, MySQL, NoSQL, IndexDB,

MongoDB, Bash

#### **PROJECTS**

### Fair Weather Hiking | Github | https://fair-weather-hiking.herokuapp.com/login

- Hiking App developed in React to display hike weather conditions and provide user specific hiking statistics
- Participated with a team of 4 in all phases of the development life cycle, focusing on coding, testing, and debugging.
- Created and developed remotely, collaborating with team members using Zoom and Slack
- Created the app concept and pitched it to team members, who agreed to develop the idea into a full application.
- Developed and organized API calls and completed hike info tracking.
- Spearheaded app demonstration and presented final product to peers and industry professionals
- React, Hiking Project API, Open Weather API, MongoDB, Mongoose, Express, Node.js, Redux, and Materialize CSS used for this project

#### Get Outside | Github | https://bmalkmus.github.io/getOutsideApp/

- Collaborated with a team of 3 to develop a Javascript app allowing a user to plan a day at a park and a meal from a restaurant
- Individual contributions include the creation of the the app concept, API Calls, and search form functionality created with Javascript
- Led a demonstration of the app to peers and a teacher, and held a Q&A after the demo.
- Javascript, jQuery, Seattle Parks API, Zomato API, Materialize CSS, and HTML used for this project

#### Employee Directory Github | https://mrbemployeedb.herokuapp.com/

- Created Interactive Employee Database app developed in React as a solo project to optimize employee data retrieval
- Developed search bar which allows the user to search employees by first name, last name, or location
- Designed sort function which allows the user to sort by years of service ascending or descending
- React, HTML, Javascript, and CSS used for this project

#### EXPERIENCE

## Web Development Volunteer The Max Foundation

September 2020 - Present

Seattle, WA

Provided technical support for the Max Foundations' first all digital Maximize Life Gala. Implemented additional Javascript features and customized CSS to the Gala website via the Clickbid platform. *Key Accomplishments:* 

- Successfully implemented additional Javascript features not supported by the Clickbid platform.
- Modified the default CSS to align web design with the Max Foundations' aesthetics
- Worked with the Senior Development Manager to ensure the Foundations' needs were being met and to collaborate on additional improvements to the website.
- Provided flexible support as requirements changed based on feedback from throughout the organization.

# Inventory Control Specialist Costco Wholesale

February 2018 - Present

Issaquah, WA

Provided logistical and operational support to vendors and international warehouses for supply chain tactics. Ensured product compliance and streamlined product standards protocols in international marketplaces. *Key Accomplishments:* 

- Established relationships with vendors to ensure customer satisfaction and resolve supply chain issues
- Successfully negotiated and supported vendor funded markdowns and promotions of key products.
- Contributed to successful openings in new markets including China and Western Australia, with higher than projected sales
- Drove continual sales increases through introduction of new items and timely in store promotions, meeting or exceeding annual projections in most markets

## Tax Accountant Costco Wholesale

July 2013 - February 2018

Issaguah, WA

Independently managed and reviewed sales tax refund claims for online and in-store purchases as a forward facing customer service representative. Participated in state audits of sales tax returns.

Key Accomplishments:

- Successfully automated aspects of the sales tax refund claim process increasing efficiency and reducing processing time by 66%
- Contributed to department tax knowledge through deep research on new and upcoming sales tax issues, ensuring readiness to tackle future upcoming issues.
- Earned the trust of retail customers through strong customer service, continual communication, and minimizing tax refund processing times

### Reservation Agent

November 2012 - July 2013

Costco Travel Issaguah, WA

Arranged and coordinated cruise reservations for customers. Maintained product expertise to ensure customers have the best possible experience.

Key Accomplishments:

- Received Excellence Award twice in two quarters of eligibility
- Successfully placed reservations and made adjustments based on customer needs.

#### **EDUCATION**

**Bootcamp Certificate:** University of Washington Professional and Continuing Education, Seattle, WA A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

**Bachelors of Arts:** Western Washington University, Bellingham, WA Four year university degree focused on political science, economics and policy.

**Politics Exchange Program:** University of Hull, Hull, East Yorkshire, UK Single Semester Foreign Exchange, studying British Politics and History